Finding Aid for Department of Women’s Studies (University of Michigan) records, 1972-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Program Documents
  - Conferences and Events
    - Event Files
      - Lutkehaus Film Series 1995 (Box 6)
      - Martin Luther King Day Activities 1995, 1994-1995 (Box 6)
      - McGuigan Award: Maylei Blackwell 2005 (Box 6)
      - McGuigan Award: Sherry Ortner 2004 (Box 6)
      - McGuigan Award: Wendy Wasserstein 1994 (Box 6)
      - Midlife Series, Fall 1989, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
      - Molas: Kuna Women's Visions 2004 (Box 6)
      - Multicultural, Anti-Racist Agenda for Women's Studies 1990-1991 (Box 6)
      - Peggy McIntosh Lecture 1992 (Box 6)
      - Programming 1999-2000 (Box 6)
      - Research Interests of Faculty 1986 (Box 6)
      - Sponsored and Co-Sponsored Programming in Women's Studies 1991 (Box 6)
      - Women's History Month 1995 (Box 6)
      - Women of Color Speaker Series 1994-1996 (Box 6)
      - Women Rule Report 2001 (Box 6)
      - Women's Studies Summit 2004 (Box 6)
      - Zoo Zoo Chronicles 1990-1992 (Box 6)
    - Speaker Files
      - Abu-Lughod, Lila 1990-1991 (Box 6)
      - Buchanan, Beverly 2005 (Box 6)
      - Collins, Patricia Hill 1994 (Box 6)
      - Conkey, Meg 1992 (Box 6)
      - Eshete, Almaz 1991 (Box 6)
      - Fattah, Hala 1991-1992 (Box 6)
      - Fulton, Alice undated (Box 6)
      - Fregoso, Rosa Linda 1994 (Box 6)
      - Gaines, Jane 1994 (Box 6)
      - Gole, Nilufer 1992 (Box 6)
      - Hirsch, Marianne 1993 (Box 6)
      - Hooks, Bell and Gloria Watkins 1991-1992 (Box 6)
      - Kampen, Natalie 1991 (Box 6)
      - Matthew, Annu 2004 (Box 6)
      - McKay, Nellie 1991 (Box 6)
      - Miller, Nancy K. 1996 (Box 6)
      - Noujaim, Jehane 2006 (Box 6)
      - Peteet, Julie 1993 (Box 6)
      - Romero, Mary 1991-1992 (Box 6)
      - Trotman Reid, Pamela 1995 (Box 6)
  - Historical Documents (Box 6)
    - 20th Anniversary Documents 1992 (Box 6)
    - Documents 1980s, 1980-1987 (Box 6)
    - Documents: Overview of the Women's Studies Program and Proposal for a Certificate Program in Women's Studies 1978-1983 (Box 6)
    - Program Enhancement Initiative 1999 (Box 6)
    - Program Review 1989 (Box 6)
    - Reports of the Ad Hoc Committee on Women's Issues (Agenda for the 1990s) 1988 (Box 6)
    - Selected Materials for the External Review 1989, 4 folders (Box 6)
    - U.S. Department of Education Contract Modification 1989 (Box 7)
  - Projects
    - Differences Among Women Documents 1991 (Box 7)
    - Differences Among Women Documents 1993-1995, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Differences Among Women Selection Letters 1994 (Box 7)
    - Differences Among Women Submissions 1994, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Feminist Practice 1993-1995 (Box 7)
    - Feminist Scholarship: Thinking Through the Disciplines Documents 1987-1991 (Box 7)
    - Feminist Scholarship: Thinking Through the Disciplines Final Report 1992 (Box 7)
    - Women's Initiative Group (WING) Curriculum Task Force 1988-1990, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Women's Initiative Group (WING) Documents 1986-1990, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Women of Color Documents 1987-1990 (Box 7)
    - Women of Color Faculty Mailing Lists 1986-1989 (Box 7)
    - Women of Color Potential Speakers 1987-1990 (Box 7)
    - Women of Color in the Academy Documents 1994-1996, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Women of Color in the Academy Project Management Documents 1995-1996 (Box 7)
- Publications
  The Publications (1974-2006, 1.0 linear foot, plus 1 outsize folder) series is arranged alphabetically and includes fliers, newsletters, posters, programs, and other assorted publications.
  - Annual Activities Report 1995-1996, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Event fliers 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Event fliers 1999-2005, 6 folders (Box 7)
  - Events Calendar 2001-2002 (Box 7)
  - Exhibiting Gender program 2000 (Box 7)
  - Interdepartmental Doctoral Program in Women's Studies and History brochure undated (Box 7)
  - Mailings 1990-1993, 7 folders (Box 7)
  - Mailings 1993-1997, 10 folders (Box 8)
  - Mailing List Appeal 1983 (Box 8)
  - Michigan Occasional Papers in Women's Studies brochure undated (Box 8)
  - Newsletter 1996 (Box 8)
  - Newsletter 1998 (Box 8)
  - Newsletter 2003 (Box 8)
  - Newsletter 2006 (Box 8)
  - Papers in Women's Studies, Vol. 1, No. 1 1974 (Box 8)
  - Papers in Women's Studies, Vol. 1, No. 2 1974 (Box 8)
  - Plots & Plans: What's Cooking in Feminist Scholarship?, conference brochure 1991 (Box 8)
  - Plots & Plans: What's Cooking in Feminist Scholarship?, conference program 1991 (Box 8)
  - Posters
    - 1978-1979 (Folder Bimu C46)
    - Gender, Power, and Representation Posters 2002 (Folder Bimu C46)
  - Program brochures 1991 (Box 8)
  - Program brochures undated (Box 8)
  - Survival in Ann Arbor: Information for Women in Ann Arbor undated (Box 8)
  - Women and Memory conference brochure 1986 (Box 8)
  - Women Writing Culture: Anthropology and its Other Voices brochure 1991 (Box 8)
  - Women's Studies Library Informational Bookmark undated (Box 8)
  - Women's Resources 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Women's Studies Program Winter 2000 Course Offerings, 2000 (Box 8)
  - Zoo Zoo Chronicles program 1992 (Box 8)
- Women's Studies Library
  The Women's Studies Library series (1978-2000, 0.75 linear feet,) is divided into two sub-series arranged alphabetically: Executive Committee and General Files. Executive Committee (1990-1998, 0.1 feet) consists of correspondence and memos to the Library Executive Committee. General Files (1978-2000, 0.65 feet) consists of correspondence, documents, logbooks, and manuals related to the management of the Women's Studies Library, including the re-evaluation of the library in 1996-1997. The annotated bibliography produced by the Women of Color project is included.
  - Executive Committee
    - Correspondence to the Executive Committee 1995-1996 (Box 8)
    - Memos on Establishing the Video Collection 1993 (Box 8)
    - Memos to the Executive Committee 1990-1998 (Box 8)
  - General Files
    - Acquisitions Criteria 1992 (Box 8)
    - Alumni Center 1992 (Box 8)
    - Booksale and Donation Documents 1999 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence 1989-1995 (Box 8)
    - Donor Correspondence 1978-2000, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Documents 1994-2000, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Friends of the Library undated (Box 8)
    - Future of the Women's Studies Library 1996-1997 (Box 8)
    - Hartfield Rare Books Donation 1997 (Box 8)
    - Library Manual 1997, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Library Manual Policy Changes 1997-1998 (Box 8)
    - Logbooks 1993-1997, 4 folders (Box 8)
    - Logbook 1999-2000 (Box 9)
    - Logbook undated (Box 9)
    - Manuals and Projects, pre-1996 undated (Box 9)
    - Memos to Staff 1997-1998 (Box 9)
    - Newsletters December 1999-March 2000 (Box 9)
    - User Survey Report 1997 (Box 9)
    - Winter 2000 Faculty and Program Information, November 1999 (Box 9)
    - Withdrawn Periodicals Evaluations 1995 (Box 9)
    - Women of Color: An Annotated Bibliography 1991 (Box 9)
- Visual Materials
  Visual Materials (undated-2004, 0.1 linear feet,) is a small series arranged alphabetically containing visual materials separated from the analog files. This includes the" Through My Lens" VHS from the Women of Color in the Academy Project, and photographs from the Jewish Women Writing Feminism lecture.
  - Women of Color in the Academy: Through My Lens 1997, VHS (Box 9)
  - Jewish Women Writing Feminism 2004, photographs and CD (Box 9)
- Archived Website
  The Department of Women's Studies Website series documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the Department of Women's Studies includes important news and announcements, publications (such as newsletters and course catalogs), and information about admissions, curriculum, degree requirements, faculty, and the overall mission of the Department. The website series is arranged chronologically starting in 2010. This archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.
  - Web Capture July 26, 2012-[ongoing]
Related Material
The Women's Studies Department at times collaborates with other departments on campus for its projects. For related materials on the Women of Color and Women's Initiative Group (WING), consult the Center for the Education of Women (CEW). The Institute for Research on Women and Gender (IRWG) grew out of the Women's Studies Program in 1995 and continues to work closely with the department.
The Department of Women's Studies Website series documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the Department of Women's Studies includes important news and announcements, publications (such as newsletters and course catalogs), and information about admissions, curriculum, degree requirements, faculty, and the overall mission of the Department. The website series is arranged chronologically starting in 2010. This archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.